Neal Sunners

SVP Innovation & Chief Information Officer International at Avis Budget Group International neal.sunners@gmail.com

Summary

Senior Executive with successful career at board level (roles such as CIO, COO and Managing Director) across a variety industries from start-ups to established global organisations. Highly experienced in shaping and delivering major business and technology driven change programmes within omni channel organisations, specialising in both b2b and b2c.

Has led Global and Pan-European programmes encompassing: Application Development, Technical Operations, Data Centre Management, Product Management, Product Strategy, Product Development, Business Operations, Customer Service Operations all incorporating both captive and outsourced delivery mechanisms:

- Led due diligence and integration teams for many acquisitions leading to investments in excess of 5 billion dollars
- Managed technology teams in excess of a 1000 people, on a globally distributed basis combining employed and outsourced resources
- Managed product teams in excess of 100 Product Consultants with specific accountability for product strategy, product management, product deployment and in market product support services.
- Managed investment and operational budgets in excess of 100 million dollars per annum.
- Engaged in investor relations leading to securing investments is excess of 200 million dollars
- Conceived, acquired board approval and brought to delivery investment projects that required in excess of 50 million dollars of specific investment

Specialties: Delivery of Technology, Product Management and Strategy on a global basis. Business / Organisation Transformation. Change Leadership. Technology / Product Due Diligence

Experience

SVP Innovation & Chief Information Officer International at Avis Budget Group International

August 2016 - Present (8 months)

Dual Reporting Line to Chief Innovation Officer & President International Markets Member of global leadership teams for IT & Innovation

CIO International at Avis Budget Group

December 2013 - Present (3 years 4 months)

- Reporting to the President International Markets

- Member of Global IT Leadership team
- Efficient operation of a 300 + strong IT organisation distributed across EMEA and APAC covering all technology disciplines
- Annual budget of circa €80 million
- Introduced "industry first" tablet apps and smartphone apps
- Delivered award winning websites across multiple brands on a pan EMEA basis
- Completed rationalisation of 14 distributed data centres into two central data centres
- Led due diligence and integration of four significant acquisitions

Director at Enness Consultancy Ltd

June 2010 - November 2013 (3 years 6 months)

Established as a vehicle for independent consulting and interim management positions.

Delivering services to cover - definition and delivery of technology / product across a variety of industries and ranging from startups to large global companies and Private Equity Groups.

Successful record of delivery to organisations in the UK, Europe and United States of America.

Avis Budget Group, UK (Interim Group IT Director) - April 2012 – November 2013. Delivered Organisation transformation with optimized use of outsourcing, introduced SDLC processes and attained SOx compliance and providing multi million savings per annum.

APTCO, Washington DC, USA - September 2011 – March 2012. Retained to provide leadership for Business Development within Product Market Development and Product Strategy Development Department. Produced detailed analysis of key industry trends and business processes and ultimately concept papers and business cases for major investments.

CollinsonGroup, London, UK – November 2010 – May 2011. Led a Programme to review Product Strategy, Management Framework, Processes and Delivery Methodologies. Delivered detailed recommendation for organization restructuring and a forward looking Product Strategy

Permira, Barcelona, Spain - June - August 2010 - led the due diligence (technology and product) for the €250 M acquisition of eDreams a pan European online travel agency. Delivered detailed analysis of capability together with detailed recommendations for organization / process improvement post acquisition.

Group Vice President, Product & Services (Denver / Langley, UK) at Travelport October 2008 - May 2010 (1 year 8 months)

- Reporting to CMO
- Effective client and stakeholder management across a complex matrix organisation
- Efficient operation of a 100 person global shared service. Successful delivery to key service metrics
- Introduced industrial strength Product Management Processes
- Restructure Product & Services organisation, replacing over 20% of staff with new entrants, thus driving change into the broader organisation.
- Managed investment budget of over \$80 million
- Introduced two new products that were accepted for innovation awards by industry analysts
- Introduced "industry first" merchandising solutions
- Engaged in investor relations leading to securing investments is excess of 200 million dollars

VP Point of Sale Technologies (Denver, CO) at Travelport

September 2007 - September 2008 (1 year 1 month)

- Reporting to CIO
- Development / Operational responsibility for over 300 development staff across a portfolio of Products
- Managed annual budget in excess of \$30 million.
- Identified, managed the due diligence and integration of G2 Switchworks technology and staff.
- Managed integration / retirement of many solutions post merger with Worldpsan
- Conceived, acquired board approval and brought to delivery investment projects that required in excess of 50 million dollars of specific investment
- Client facing role, developing relationship with executive teams of significant customers.

VP IT Strategy / Head of Development (Denver, CO) at Galileo

August 2006 - August 2007 (1 year 1 month)

- Reporting to CIO
- Led technology due diligence and planning teams for acquisition of Worldspan by Travelport (Blackstone) largest integration in the travel industry.
- Managed all software development for Galileo worldwide with over 1000 staff distributed in development centres in Denver, Bangalore, Mumbai, Chicago, London, Sydney
- Managed budget exceeding \$80 million
- Delivered improved quality of solutions, on time and within budget.

CIO - Consumer Travel Division (London, UK) at Cendant

March 2004 - July 2006 (2 years 5 months)

- Reported to the CEO.
- Managed a global team of over 300 staff with centres in London, Sydney and Delhi.
- Managed multiple data centres in London, Sydney and Delhi.
- Defined and executed a remediation plan for ebookers pan European web sites, post acquisition exceeding all targets and supporting a growth in revenues.
- Managed integration into Orbitz Worldwide Organisation post acquisition and integration..

- Led technology due diligence and integration on several acquisitions (over \$2 billion dollars of investment)

VP Technology - CIO International Markets (Langley, UK) at Cendant

February 2002 - February 2004 (2 years 1 month)

- Reporting to President International Markets.
- Dotted line report to Global CIO (based in Denver) and Corporate CIO (based in London)
- Developed and maintained productive relationship with CIO's of significant clients
- Responsible for delivery and support of all technology outside of North America with a distributed team of over 100 staff (London, Sydney, Rome, Copenhagen, Dehli)
- Managed budget in excess of \$30 million.
- Led due diligence and managed the integration of technology of 7 acquisitions (an overall investment of approx. \$1 billion)

Chief Operations Officer, (Reading, UK) at TravelNet / Aerotech

February 2000 - January 2002 (2 years)

- Start up company providing Travel technology on a global basis
- Member of the executive team and led the raising of \$5 million from VC's in Hong Kong (inc IBM, HSBC).
- Developed solution and deployed in 9 languages on a global basis.
- Managed the acquisition and integration of TISS.com, Flights.com and Deckchair.com
- Managed budgets in excess of \$2 million

Managing Director, (Crowthorne, UK) at Rubicon Software

February 1996 - January 2000 (4 years)

- Junior Partner in small software house.
- Responsible for all aspects of the business save for software development.
- Grew the business from £100 k pa turnover (2 members of staff) to over £1 million pa with over 40 staff.
- Migrated the business from the not for profit sector to CRM and web applications in the finance sector.

Technical Services Manager (Trowbridge, UK) at Academy - Capita Group

February 1994 - February 1996 (2 years 1 month)

- Reported to Chief Executive
- Responsible for all aspects of Technical Operations and Software Maintenance.
- Migrated software solutions from "legacy" mainframes to open systems.
- Responsible for a budget in excess of £2 million.

Senior Business Consultant (Oxford, UK) at Capita Managed Services

February 1993 - February 1994 (1 year 1 month)

- Reported to Sales Director
- Capita is an IT outsourcing management company
- Introduced new time management principles and software solutions to bring a loss making account back into profit.

- Continued as product Manager for local government solutions acquired from AT&T.
- Capita acquired other Government Software Houses and formed Academy Software

Business Unit Manager (Swindon, UK) at AT&T Istel (acquired WPA LTD)

February 1991 - February 1993 (2 years 1 month)

- Reported to the Sales Director
- Awarded the contract to supply Electoral Registration system to N. Ireland Secretary of State largest contract of its kind in the UK
- Responsible for a "discreet" organisation within the company focusing on government software.
- Presented to the ANC in Johannesburg (after the election of Nelson Mandela) on the use of computerised solutions in free and fair elections.
- The local government software business unit was acquired by Capita Managed Services

Product Manager (Cheltenham, UK) at WPA Ltd

July 1989 - February 1991 (1 year 8 months)

- Reported to the Managing Director
- Designed, developed and delivered the first networked PC Electoral Registration system in the UK
- Captured over 20% of the available market in its first year of operation.
- Responsible for all aspects of the product including design, development, sales and customer support.
- Enabled MD / owner to sell his company to AT&T

Electoral and Office Services Manager at English Local Government

July 1979 - July 1989 (10 years 1 month)

Over a period of ten years I worked for the Local Authorities in Liverpool, Oxford and Swindon in a series of Administrative roles specialising in the management of elections for all levels of Government both in the UK and abroad.

Skills & Expertise

Executive Leadership

Change Leadership

Outsource Management

Mergers & Acquisitions

Program Management

E-commerce

Mergers

Change Management

Strategy

Leadership

Business Development

Outsourcing

Business Transformation

IT Strategy

Product Management

CRM

IT Management

Strategic Partnerships

Data Center

Start-ups

SaaS

Enterprise Architecture

Management

Executive Management

Stakeholder Management

Mobile Devices

Strategic Planning

Project Planning

Product Development

B₂B

Analysis

Software Development

Team Building

Integration

Business Intelligence

Vendor Management

Business Process Improvement

IT Outsourcing

Business Analysis

Security

Managed Services

Business Strategy

Customer Relationship Management (CRM)

Education

University of Pennsylvania - The Wharton School

CEO Leadership program, 2005 - 2005

Henley Business School

Essentials of Finance & Accounting, 2004 - 2004

Oxford Brookes University

Diploma in Public Administration, 1984 - 1987

University of Liverpool

Certificate in Public Administration, 1980 - 1982

St Margarets High School, Liverpool

9 "O" and 4 "A" Levels, 1972 - 1979

Interests

 $Swim,\,Bike,\,Run\,\,(\,\,Compete\,\,in\,\,Triathlons).$

Skiing, Football

Neal Sunners

SVP Innovation & Chief Information Officer International at Avis Budget Group International neal.sunners@gmail.com



7 people have recommended Neal

"Neal and I joined Avis Budget Group within 2 weeks of each other, initially we were peers but he then became my Boss within 18 months and has been for almost 3 years. In the 4 years we've worked together Neal has exhibited he is a unique leader who excels in both IT Strategy but perhaps more importantly Business Strategy. He demonstrated his strategic and leadership abilities by driving the transformation agenda the ABG business needs whilst maintaining that fine balance of keeping everyone engaged during difficult periods. He is always willing to take on challenges to ensure we focused on doing the right things for the Business and breaking down the typical Technology barriers to ensure engagement and sponsorship of initiatives particularly at Board and C-Level. The other initiative he has led has been driving the introduction of an Innovative culture with the group. In the 4 years we've been working together he lead the the replacement of our Digital platforms but has now taken that approach to help shape Mobility, Payment and Customer Strategies that will grow the business by embracing business change via new technologies. Whilst a technologist at heart one of his mantras has been we are in business to deliver a service and he ensures all of his teams retain focus on this. I would have no hesitation in recommending Neal"

— Gary Donnelly, Director of Applications Delivery - Consumer Services (Digital & Ecommerce), Avis Budget Group EMEA, reported to Neal at Avis Budget Group

"Neal was a leader who kept the team focused on execution by establishing the strategic direction and establishing "air cover". This gave the technical resources the ability to move forward aggressively. He empowered the team to execute unconstrained and yet was available when executive support was needed."

— Joan Hannan, PMP, CSM, reported to Neal at Travelport

"Neal is a strong strategic global thinker able to convert the strategic theory into real delivery. He has a natural ability to bridge what a business needs into pragmatic and clear Product and Technology plans. He is a strong and charismatic leader who is able to build and motivate teams to deliver. His broad experiences in M and A, large integration projects and key Product initiatives make him a sound choice in leading a technology or Product team. I would have no hesitation in recommending Neal to any business looking for a Head of Technology or Product."

— **Keith Woodcock**, managed Neal at Galileo

"Neal can envision the desired outcomes of complex and challenging business problems long before others. Comfortable at all levels of management, he is an expert at persuasively and eloquently presenting creative and financially solid solutions. Neal is passionate, committed, and smart. He would be a valuable player in any organization from start-up to large corporate."

— Beckie Watson, worked with Neal at Galileo

"I had the pleasure of providing legal advice to Neal when he was head of product development at Galileo/ Travelport. Neal always brought a fact-based, no-nonsense, and pragmatic approach to problem-solving. I appreciated his direct communication style, his perspicacity, and his ability to cut through the clutter and analyze issues based on how decisions would actually impact the business. His ability to attract talented people and get them focused on delivery -- despite institutional challenges -- is evidence of his considerable leadership abilities and charisma. If you are looking for a top-calibre CIO, Neal should be on your short list."

— **Randal Reid**, worked with Neal at Galileo

"Neal is a leader who excels at motivating and keeping his team and peers focused on devising, delivering and managing solutions and infrastructures that exceed the business' expectations. I appreciated Neal's guidance and support in delivering innovative traveller solutions that address all (online and offline) customer touch points through the effective use of business focused technology. Neal was also very effective in driving significant organisational change supporting the creation of strong, talented delivery-focused teams in a very dynamic and complex business environment. I highly recommend Neal."

— Leon Koutsovasilis, reported to Neal at Cendant

"Neal is a smart, energetic executive who has a quick grasp of the landscape and knows how to work through an organisation to get quality results. He is always well liked and respected by his peers and superiors"

— **Robert Wiseman**, worked directly with Neal at Cendant

Contact Neal on LinkedIn